<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Mental</title><description>This is the landing page for Mental. Mental is an iPad app that allows you to draw concept maps, beautify them, and export them in pdf format.</description><link>https://your-website-url.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 4 Apr 2022 15:17:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Mon, 4 Apr 2022 15:17:45 +0200</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://your-website-url.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Concept%20Mapping</guid><title>Concept Mapping</title><description>Mental is a concept mapping app for the iPad..</description><link>https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Concept%20Mapping</link><pubDate>Sat, 2 Apr 2022 20:07:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Concept Mapping</h2><p>Mental is a <strong>concept mapping app</strong> for the iPad.</p><p><strong>Concept maps</strong> organize knowledge in the form of a graph of concepts.</p><p>Concepts are represented as a noun phrase enclosed in a rectangular box.</p><p>They are connected to other concept boxes by links labeled with a verb or conjunction. These links represent <strong>relationships</strong> between the connected concepts.</p><p>Concept boxes may have relationships to and from several other concept boxes, creating a graph of concepts, or <strong>concept map</strong>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://your-website-url.com/posts/version152</guid><title>Version 1.5.2 is out!</title><description>Release notes for version 1.5.2.</description><link>https://your-website-url.com/posts/version152</link><pubDate>Sat, 2 Apr 2022 20:07:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Version 1.5.2 is out!</h1><p>Version 1.5.2 of Mental is out:</p><ul><li>built for iOS 15,</li><li>fixes import bug.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Mental%20Features</guid><title>Mental Features</title><description>Concepts and Relationships.</description><link>https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Mental%20Features</link><pubDate>Sat, 2 Apr 2022 20:06:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Mental Features</h2><p>Users create concept maps as autosaved documents. In a concept map, they are able to create and remove concept boxes, edit the enclosed text, and move the boxes at will around a zoomable and pannable canvas.</p><p>They can create relationships to connect the concepts, a relationship being represented by at least three graphical objects:</p><ul><li>an editable label signifying the relationship;</li><li>one or more edges connecting the "subject" concepts to the label;</li><li>one or more edges connecting the label to the "object" concepts.</li></ul><p>Users are able to move the labels at will, the edge connections being preserved. They may remove relationships as a whole, or individual edges while preserving the relationship.</p><p>Other features:</p><ul><li>export to pdf and sharing</li><li>map style chooser (font, color scheme)</li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Editing%20Maps</guid><title>Editing Maps</title><description>Adding concepts and making connections.</description><link>https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Editing%20Maps</link><pubDate>Sat, 2 Apr 2022 20:05:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Editing Maps</h2><h3>How do I add a concept box?</h3><p>Tap the <code>+</code> button in the toolbar. This will insert a box in the middle of the visible part of the map, and open it in edition mode.</p><p>To add a box anywhere on a map, tap that location, and select <code>Add Concept</code> from the concept menu.</p><h3>How do I move one or more boxes?</h3><p>Depending on the app settings, you may have to select them first to move them.</p><p>If <code>Movement Without Selection</code> is left unchecked in the App Settings, you will have to select them first, by tapping them. Then simply drag them around.</p><p>If <code>Movement Without Selection</code> is checked in the App Settings, you can simply drag a box around, without prior selection.</p><p>The <code>Movement Without Selection</code> option adds fluidity when beginning a new map. When the map gets bigger, and you need more control, it's better to uncheck that option.</p><h3>How do I enlarge a map?</h3><p>Simply drag boxes around to enlarge the map. This will only work if you have more than one box, though.</p><h3>How do I edit the text in a box or label?</h3><p>Tap the box to select it. Tap <code>Edit</code> in its context menu. Alternatively, perform a double-tap on the box.</p><h3>How do I connect boxes?</h3><p>Tap the origin box to select it. Tap <code>Connect</code> in its context menu; the box blinks red indicating it's in connection mode. Tap the destination box to create the connection.</p><p>To add a connector without a label, perform a double-tap on the destination box, instead of a single-tap.</p><h3>How do I select one or more boxes?</h3><p>To select a single box, simply tap that box. A green ring appears, indicating the selected state.</p><p>To select multiple boxes, tap to select/deselect them. You will then be able to move or delete them in unison.</p><p>To deselect all currently selected boxes, tap an empty area of the map.</p><h3>How do I add a hyperlink to a concept box?</h3><p>Tap the box to select it. Tap <code>Edit</code> in its context menu. Alternatively, perform a double-tap on the box.</p><p>Type or paste in a valid hyperlink in the input accessory view. You can check the link by tapping the Open button in the input accessory view.</p><h3>How do I navigate to the hyperlink of a concept box?</h3><p>Tap the box to select it. Tap <code>Open link</code> in its context menu. Alternatively, perform a triple-tap on the box.</p><h3>How does snapping work?</h3><p>Snapping will help you align boxes horizontally and vertically. In addition, it lets you align connection labels with the parent and child concepts.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Styling%20Maps</guid><title>Styling Maps</title><description>Overall map style and element styles.</description><link>https://your-website-url.com/documentation/Styling%20Maps</link><pubDate>Sat, 2 Apr 2022 20:04:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Styling Maps</h2><h3>How do I style a map as a whole?</h3><p>Tap the <code>Paintbrush</code> button in the toolbar. The style menu appears, that allows you to change style settings for concepts, relationships, and connectors.</p><p>Style options include :</p><ul><li>Font face,</li><li>Text size,</li><li>Text color,</li><li>Fill color,</li><li>Stroke color,</li><li>Stroke width.</li></ul><h3>How do I style a single element or a group of elements?</h3><p>Select the elements you wish to style. Tap the <code>Paintbrush</code> button in the toolbar.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>